Association Against the Prohibition Amendment Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Association against the Prohibition Amendment Records 1917-1933
MSS11239
Association against the Prohibition Amendment
1,000 items 7 containers 2.8 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Anti-prohibition organization. Chiefly printed matter together with a copy of the group's certificate of foundation, annual reports, bibliographies of anti-prohibition writings, and a mailing list.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Organizations
Association Against the Prohibition Amendment.
Subjects
Prohibition.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records of the Association against the Prohibition Amendment were given to the Library of Congress by W. H. Slayton in 1937.
Access and Restrictions
The Association against the Prohibition Amendment Records are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Association against the Prohibition Amendment span the years 1917-1933. The bulk of the collection consists of anti-prohibition articles clipped from newspapers and magazines. Also included is the association's certificate of foundation, two annual reports, pamphlets printed by the society, bibliographies of anti-prohibition literature, and a mailing list.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged alphabetically by type of material. The anti-prohibition articles are arranged as received in two sets, alphabetically by author and alphabetically by periodical title.
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm78011239
Container List
- Annual reports 1932-1933 (Box 1)
- Articles (Box 1)
  - By author, 1929-1933 (Box 1)
    - A-E, (11 folders) (Box 1)
    - F-L, (9 folders) (Box 2)
    - M-R, (9 folders) (Box 3)
    - S-Z, (9 folders) (Box 4)
  - By title (Box 4)
    - A, 1928-1933, undated, (7 folders) (Box 4)
    - B-F, 1917-1933, undated, (17 folders) (Box 5)
    - G-R, 1917-1933, undated, (22 folders) (Box 6)
    - S-Y, 1921-1933, (9 folders) (Box 7)
- Bibliographies, 1928-1932, (4 folders) (Box 7)
- Certificate of foundation, 1931 (Box 7)
- Mailing list, 1929-1932, undated (Box 7)
- Pamphlets, 1928-1932, undated, (5 folders) (Box 7)